Guide to the Morris Schappes Papers TAM.179
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Morris Schappes Papers
1911-2004
1928-2002
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Schappes, Morris U. (Morris Urman), 1907-2004
Jochnowitz, Carol
Surovell, Esther
Chmielewski, Wendy E.
Swarthmore College
TAM.179
43.25 Linear Feet in 43 record cartons, 1 flat box, and 1 manuscript box.
Morris U. Schappes (1907-2004) was a scholar, editor and activist who was fired by the City College of New York after being investigated as a Communist Party member, and who spent over a year in prison (1943-1944) for perjury after refusing to name other Party members when testifying before an investigating committee of the New York State Legislature. He was a founder and longtime editor of the progressive, secular magazine Jewish Currents; a popular lecturer; and the author of articles, reviews, radio broadcasts, books and monographs, many of them on U.S. Jewish history. This collection contains correspondence, published and unpublished writings, clippings and other printed ephemera, photographs, research materials and documents produced by various progressive organizations. In addition, there is a considerable quantity of Jewish Currents editorial correspondence, Editorial Board minutes and administrative files.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were donated by Morris Schappes in 1996; additional materials were donated by Jewish Currents staff members Carol Jochnowitz and Esther Surovell in 2003 and 2004. Materials were transferred from the American Jewish Historical Society in 2010. An additional gift of four post cards was donated by Dr. Wendy E. Chmielewski of Swarthmore College in 2013. In 2014 non-print materials were reincorporated into this collection. In 2014 and 2018 materials were found in the repository and integrated into the collection. The accession numbers associated with these gifts are 1996.024, 2003.016, NPA.2003.016, 2004.042, NPA.2004.049, 2009.086, 2010.030, 2013.037, 2014.051, and 2018.031.
Arrangement
The collection contains the following series and subseries:
Series I: Personal Papers, 1913-2003
Series II: Jewish Currents Files, 1958-2004
Subseries IIA: Minutes
Subseries IIB: Correspondence
Subseries IIC: Administrative Files
Series III: WBAI Broadcasts, 1966-1994
Series IV: Subject Files, 1911-2004
Series V: Audio-Visual Files, 1966-2000
Subseries VA: Audio Cassettes
Subseries VB: Reel-to-Reel Tapes
Subseries VC: Video Cassettes (VHS)
Subseries VD: Audio Cassettes Addendum
Subseries VE: Reel-to-Reel Tapes Addendum
Series VI: Photographs, 1920-2002
Historical/Biographical Note
Morris U. Schappes (1907-2004) was a scholar, editor and activist who was fired by the City College of New York after being investigated as a Communist Party member, and who spent over a year in prison (1943-1944) for perjury after refusing to name other Party members when testifying before an investigating committee of the New York State Legislature. He was a founder and long-time editor of the progressive, secular magazine Jewish Currents; a popular lecturer; and the author of articles, reviews, radio broadcasts, books and monographs, many of them on U.S. Jewish history.
Born Moishe Shapshilevich in Kamenetz-Podolsk, Ukraine, Schappes spent his earliest years in Brazil and then moved with his parents to New York City in 1914. Bureaucrats reduced the family name to Schappes and his mother Americanized his name as Morris. He added the middle "U" later as part of his byline as a sportswriter on the newspaper of City College of New York (CCNY), where he graduated in 1928 and subsequently joined the faculty as an English lecturer. (He had previously attended Townsend Harris Hall High School.) He also attended Columbia University as a graduate student, earning a master's degree in 1930. In that same year, he began his sixty-two year marriage to Sonya Laffer, who died in 1992.
A longtime fixture in the world of American Communism, Schappes gained widespread attention in 1941 when he was fired, along with 40 others, from the faculty of CCNY for Communist Party membership or involvement. The school had first attempted to dismiss him in 1936 for his political activities but he was retained as the result of a student protest. Later he served 13 1/2 months (1943-1944) in prison for perjury after refusing to name other Party members before New York's Joint Legislative Committee on the State Education System (known as the Rapp-Coudert Committee). After his release from prison, Schappes worked briefly in a war production factory in Queens and, in 1946, joined with other Party activists to found the magazine Jewish Life, which became an unofficial Party organ. He supplemented his income by freelance lecturing and writing.
As a scholar, Schappes first achieved some prominence for his work on the poetry and letters of Emma Lazarus, and he published a number of books and monographs between 1944 and 1987. Having developed a strong interest in Jewish history while serving in prison, he subsequently published two broad historical studies: A Documentary History of the Jews in the United States, 1654-1877 (1950) and The Jews in the United States: A Pictorial History, 1654 to the Present (1958).
In the early 1950s, Schappes experienced another brush with government committees when the State Department began a purge of books from the shelves of overseas libraries operated by the United States Information Agency. The U.S. Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations, chaired by Senator Joseph R. McCarthy, held hearings to support McCarthy's demand that 30,000 "Communist books" be removed, including Schappes' A Documentary History of the Jews…. In April of 1953, Schappes was subpoenaed and appeared before the committee to defend his books and to attack McCarthyism.
After Nikita Krushchev's 1956 speech denouncing the misdeeds of Stalin, the subscription base of Jewish Life began slipping away and the magazine's staff joined many of the rank-and-filers in their disillusion with the Communism they had known. The result was the founding of Jewish Currents, with Morris Schappes as its editor; the journal, independent of Party discipline and financing, would become an intellectual home for an increasingly diverse base of (mostly) secular Jewish leftists.
Schappes dedicated more than four decades to Jewish Currents, and to shaping the views of its enthusiastic and loyal readership. In his "Editor's Diary" column, he reported on books, plays, films and events in the progressive Jewish movement and engaged in a number of noteworthy controversies, including a historical defense of American Jewish responses to the Holocaust; commentaries about solidarity and tensions between U.S. Jews and African-Americans; and his concerns about antisemitism in Shakespeare's The Merchant of Venice. Schappes played an active role in the day-to-day management of Jewish Currents until 2000.
Throughout his working life, he was a sought-after lecturer and commentator on Jewish affairs and wrote many articles, essays and letters to the editor in a variety of newspapers, magazines and journals. In 1981, the faculty senate of City College formally apologized for firing him and his colleagues.
Morris Schappes died in New York City on June 3, 2004. He was 97 years old.
Sources:
Douglas, Martin, "Morris Schappes, Marxist and Jewish Scholar, Dies at 97", New York Times (June 9, 2004).
Forward Staff, "Leftist Magazine Editor Morris U. Schappes, 97, Dies", Forward, http://www.jewishcurrents.org/schappes.htm, July 17, 2008.
"Morris U. Schappes, 1907-2004," Jewish Currents, July 2004.
Related Archival Materials
Investigation Files of the Rapp-Coudert Committee (TAM 533, R-7860)
Henry Foner Papers (TAM 254)
Which side were you on? the American Communist Party during the Second World War: Interview Transcripts and Summaries, 1977-1978, Maurice Isserman (OH 51 - Transcript)
Frederic Ewen Audiotape and Videotape Collection. Contains a 120-minute videotape of Morris Schappes (OH 52)
Another important source of archival material concerning the life and times of Morris Schappes is the American Jewish Historical Society (AJHS). Schappes (and Jewish Currents staff) made donations to the AJHS Library in 1968, 1979 and 2004. The 1968 donation is especially relevant as it focuses on Schappes' dealings with the Rapp-Coudert Committee and his time in prison, represented by court documents, trial notes, pamphlets, newspaper articles, press releases, and prison rules and regulations. Of particular interest is the correspondence, which includes many letters of support written during his legal battles and prison correspondence with his friends, with servicemen (1943-1946), and with his wife, Sonya. The remainder of the collection consists of materials Schappes generated and collected between 1931 and 1990 in connection with his professional work as a scholar, writer and editor. (See AJHS finding aid.)
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains correspondence, published and unpublished writings, photographs, clippings and other printed ephemera, research materials and documents produced by various progressive organizations. The Schappes Papers reveal a man of widely varying interests, radical views, strong opinions and devotion to the magazine he helped found -- Jewish Currents. The collection provides not only a glimpse into Schappes' personal life and his involvement with the American left, but also a record of the day-to-day management the magazine itself.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Access to audiovisual materials in this collection is available through digitized access copies. Researchers may view an item's original container, but the media themselves are not available for playback because of preservation concerns. Materials that have already been digitized are noted in the collection's finding aid and can be requested in our reading room. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Articles.; Newsletters.; Obituaries.; Press releases.; Minutes (administrative records); Pamphlets.; Magazines (Periodicals); Academic freedom |z New York (State) |z New York.; New York (N.Y.).; Reviews (document genre); Writings (document genre); Notes.; Research notes.; Fliers (printed matter); Correspondence.; Communism.; Antisemitism.; Holocaust, Jewish (1939-1945); Jews -- United States -- Attitudes toward Israel.; Zionism.; Anti-communist movements |z United States |x History.; Immigrants -- United States.; Jewish trade-unions.; Printed ephemera.; Essays.; Exhibition catalogs.; African Americans -- Relations with Jews.; Audiovisual materials.; Interviews.; Jewish history, life, and culture.; Clippings (information artifacts); New York (State). Legislature. Joint Legislative Committee to Investigate the Educational System of the State of New York; Foner, Philip Sheldon, 1910-1994; Foner, Henry; Foner, Moe, 1915-; Harap, Louis; Leberstein, Steven; Foner, Jack D.; Salomon, Haym, 1740-1785; Schappes, Morris U. (Morris Urman), 1907-2004; Eisenberger, Sidney; Porter, Jack Nusan; Rubenstein, Annette T.; Rose, Ernestine L. (Ernestine Louise), 1810-1892; Sarna, Jonathan; City University of New York. City College; Lazarus, Emma, 1847-1887; New York (State). Legislature. Joint Legislative Committee to Investigate the Educational System of the State of New York; Prago, Albert; Rosenberg, Ethel, 1915-1953; Rosenberg, Julius, 1918-1953; Jochnowitz, Carol; Surovell, Esther; Chmielewski, Wendy E.; Swarthmore College
- Series I: Personal Papers, 1913-2003
  Scope and Content Note
  Directly related to Morris Schappes' personal life, this series includes correspondence (1928-2002); biographical articles and brief sketches; interview transcripts and Schappes' responses to several questionnaires; items associated with the schools he attended and those where he served on the faculty -- Townsend Harris Hall High School, City College of New York (CCNY), Columbia University, Queens College, the Jefferson School and the School for Jewish Studies; documents relating his experiences with the Rapp-Coudert Committee, the Schappes Defense Committee, his time in prison and subsequent parole; materials describing his many personal appearances, lectures and speaking engagements (1943-1994); a selection of his writings -- articles, book reviews and letters to the editor; and ephemera such as identification cards, his wedding ketubah, citizenship papers and copies of personal photographs.
  Arrangement
  Folders in this series are arranged alphabetically.
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1943-1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1950-1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1971-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Appearances, Lectures, Speaking Engagements, 1987-1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Articles: Various, mention Schappes, 1943-1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Austin, Warren B., 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bibliographies: Schappes' Writings, 1982, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Biographical Articles, 1943, 1985-1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Biographical Sketches, 1939-1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Book Burning" Controversy, 1952-1954 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "Book Burning" Controversy: Schappes' Book - A Documentary History of Jews in the United States, 1654-1875, 1951-1954 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Book Burning" Controversy: Senate Subcommitte on Investigations (McCarthy) - Schappes' Appearance, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Case, Clifford: His Sister, Adelaide, and Schappes Connection, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Citizenship, Identification and Voter Registration, 1913-1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - City College of New York (CCNY), Department of English: Class Registers, 1928-1934 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - CCNY, Department of English: Class Registers, 1934-1937 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - CCNY, Department of English: Class Registers, 1938-1941 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - CCNY, Department of English: Teaching Notes and Related Material, 1929-1943 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - CCNY: Inauguration of Bernard Warren Harleston, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - CCNY: Keezer, George, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - CCNY: Schappes as Alumnus, 1948-2003 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - CCNY: Schappes as Student, 1926-1928, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - CCNY: Schappes as Teacher, 1930-1941 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - CCNY: Schappes' Yearbook, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Columbia University: Schappes' Grade Reports, 1928-1932 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Condolences (Death of Sonya Laffer Schappes, 1992) (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Condolences (Death of Sonya Laffer Schappes, 1992), 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1928-1939 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1940-1945 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1946-Jun 1946 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, Jul 1946-Dec 1946 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1969 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1980-1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1996 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1998-2002, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Communist Party USA (Eugene Dennis), 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Dispute re: AJHS/NYPL Exhibit "Jewish Life in America...", 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Donations of Materials to Various Repositories, 1968-1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Fast, Howard, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: re: Salomon, Haym, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Donations and Sponsorships, 1946-1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Donations and Sponsorships, 1980-2000, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Eisenberger, Sidney (Rapp-Coudert Victim): Correspondence with Schappes, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Eisenberger, Sidney: Interview Transcript, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Eisenberger, Sidney: "Political Memoirs..." and Brief Essays, 1973, 1979, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Ephemera and Artifacts, 1957-1999, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Goldstein, Jonah, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Hearings: Committee on Un-American Activities (House), "Communist Methods of Infiltration", 1953 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Hearings: Subcommittee on Investigations of the Committee on Gov't Operations (Senate) - "State Dept. Information Program...", 1953 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Interview (and Associated Correspondence) by Dr. Robert W. Iversen, Drake University, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Jefferson School and the School for Jewish Studies, 1945-1956 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Ketubah and Other Personal Items, [1930]-1993, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - New Jewish Agenda: Unsung Hero Award, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - New York Historical Association: Relationship with Schappes, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Oral History: Cornell University - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Oral History / Interview Transcripts: "An Interview with Morris U. Schappes. By Elliot L. Jurist", 1987 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Oral History / Interview Transcripts: Interview with Morris Schappes by Lauren Strauss, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Oral History / Interview Transcripts: Morris Schappes Interviewed on I.B. Singer (Janet Hadda), 1992 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Oral History / Interview Transcripts: "Morris U. Schappes: Distinguished Radical American Jewish Historian", 1992 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Oral History / Interview Transcripts: "Morris U. Schappes, Jews of New York" - William E. Weiner Oral History Library, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Oral History / Interview Transcripts: "The Reminiscences of Morris U. Schappes", 1983 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Parole, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - People of the State of New York v. Morris U. Schappes: Amicus Curiae, National Lawyers Guild (NYC Chapter), [1942] (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - People of the State of New York v. Morris U. Schappes: Appellant's Brief (Supreme Court, State of NY, Appellate Division), [1943] (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - People of the State of New York v. Morris U. Schappes: Brief for Defendant-Appellant (Court of Appeals, NY), [1943] (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Personal Photographs (Photocopies), 1920-1985, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Prison, 1941, 1943-1945 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Queens College History Department: Schappes' Activities (I), 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Queens College History Department: Schappes' Activities (II), 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Queens College History Department: Course Evaluations, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Queens College: Joseph S. Murphy (President), 1973-1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Questionnaire re: Influence of Anti-Communism on American Life (Tillet): Schappes' Response, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Questionnaire (with Schappes' Response): Christian Science Monitor Study of McCarthy Hearings, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Questionnaire (with Schappes' Response) and Survey Report "The Fifth Amendment Plea before Congressional Committees Investigating Subversion...", 1956, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Rapp-Coudert Committee (Joint Legislative Committee to Investigate the Educational System of the State of New York), 1940-1945 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Rapp-Coudert Committee, 1983-1987 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Rapp-Coudert / Brooklyn College: Morais, Herbert M., 1983 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Rapp-Coudert / City College: "Communists in Higher Education: CCNY and Brooklyn College on the Eve of the Rapp-Coudert Investigation, 1935-1939", 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Rapp-Coudert / City College: Finley, Moses, 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Rapp-Coudert / City College: Foner, Philip, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Rapp-Coudert / City College: "The Rapp-Coudert Committee and City College 1940-1942" by Dr. Stephen Leberstein, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Rapp-Coudert / City College: Vindication, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Rapp-Coudert / City College: Vindication, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Rapp-Coudert / City College: Vindication, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Rapp-Coudert / City College: Vindication (Correspondence), 1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Rapp-Coudert / City College: Vindication (Correspondence), 1982 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Rapp-Coudert: Excerpt from Paper by Mark Leiner, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Rapp-Coudert: Reunion Film, 1995-1998 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Riesman, David (and Morris Schappes), 1962 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Relief from Disabilities (Right to Register to Vote after Felony Conviction), 1945-1977 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Rosenberg, Ethel and Julius: Schappes' Attendance at Funeral, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - "Schappes Case": Photocopies from Jonah J. Goldstein Papers (AJHS), 1941-1943, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Schappes Defense Committee, 1941-1945 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Schappes Defense Committee: Appeals to Governor Thomas E. Dewey, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Schappes, Morris U. v. The Board of Higher Education fo the City of New York: Brief for Plaintiff-Appellant (Supreme Court NYState), [1941] (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Schappes, Morris U. v. The People of the State of New York (Supreme Court of the US), 1943 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Schappes, Sonya Laffer: Citizenship, 1926-1930, 1971, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Schappes, Sonya: Schappes' Notes on Hospitalization, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - School for Democracy, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Selective Service, 1940, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - South Side School of Jewish Studies, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Seventy-Fifth Birthday, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Surgery, Mount Sinai Hospital, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Teachers' Retirement, 1933, 1941-1946 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Teaching Notes: Literature (I), 1934-1949, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Teaching Notes: Literature (II), 1934-1949, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Townsend Harris Alumni Association, 1983-1995, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Townsend Harris Alumni Association / A. Philip Randolph High School: Relationship, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Townsend Harris Hall of Fame Induction, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Townsend Harris Hall: Schappes' Yearbook, 1923 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Writings: "Anti-Semitism and Reaction, 1795-1800", 1948 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Writings: Articles - New Masses, 1941-1946 (Box 6, Folder 9)